Hi again! In this video,
we'll go into data analysis
and how project managers
use it to make informed
decisions throughout a project.
We use data every day to help us
make both simple and important
decisions in our lives.
For example, imagine that you're
saving money for a big purchase.
Maybe you decided
that the best way to
reach your goal sooner
is to create a budget.
After spending time
reviewing your budget,
perhaps you find that your weekly
expenses are higher than
your weekly allowances
and that many of
your expenses are from
ordering food and dining out.
You realize that in order
for you to reach your goal,
you'll need to start spending
less money on eating out
and find more cost-effective
ways to buy food.
With this new information,
you've found a way to save
up for your big purchase.
Similar to how you might create
an adjusted budget to
reach a desired outcome,
it's your role as a
project manager to select
appropriate data to help
inform your decision-making.
You can do this using a
process called data analysis.
Data analysis is the
process of collecting
and organizing information
to help draw conclusions.
It's used to solve problems,
make informed decisions,
and support goals.
Businesses use data analysis
to reveal important insights and
patterns within their data that
help inform actions
and drive results.
Gathering data is only
part of the process.
The other part is
analyzing the data.
What you learn from
your analysis becomes
knowledge that powers smart
solutions for your project.
Project managers will often
apply data analysis to look for
repeated behaviors and to find
a solution based on
data predictions.
For example,
let's imagine that a ride-share
company has a group of
data analysts working on using
patterns in rider behavior
to improve customer support.
They noticed a high
demand for drivers
midweek during rush hour
in one specific city.
As a result, riders
are having a hard time
getting drivers to pick
them up during peak hours.
As a project manager,
you've been asked to come
up with a solution to
help meet the increased
demand for drivers.
You work with your
team to determine
which data points would be
most appropriate to review.
You might decide to track
peak traffic times, the number of
average daily rider requests,
and the number of
available drivers.
These data points
can help inform how
to solve for the high
demand during rush hour.
After analyzing the data,
your team realizes that one
solution could be to offer
incentives to drivers to pick up
riders in the city
during peak times.
The new incentives make
drivers feel appreciated,
and the increase in drivers
increases customer satisfaction.
And you came to this solution
thanks to the insights
gleaned from data analysis.
In this example, you
collected types of
data: qualitative
and quantitative.
Quantitative data includes
statistical and numerical facts
about the number of rider
requests that came in.
Requests in the city increased at
specific points over
a period of time.
The other data is qualitative
data, which describes
the subjective
qualities or things
that can't be measured
with numerical data,
like user feedback about
the service or product.
In project management,
you will use
both qualitative data and
quantitative data points
to inform decisions,
make improvements,
and share insights.
Coming up, you'll learn
how to tell stories using
data and effective ways to
present. Meet you there.